<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>pedagogy on CJFE</title>
    <link>https://cjfe.me/tags/pedagogy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in pedagogy on CJFE</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cjfe.me/tags/pedagogy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Concepts of Learning (Series) - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://cjfe.me/post/concepts-of-learning-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cjfe.me/post/concepts-of-learning-part-1/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;series-introduction&#34;&gt;Series Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve been delving into the theory of education (pedagogy). This is a topic that has interested me for a while now; learning anything and everything is a hobby of mine, including learning to be a better learner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a 3-year-old daughter and, like any parent, I want the best for her. Parents are a child&amp;rsquo;s first teacher; a privilege and responsibility that should be taken seriously. It is this, as well as my passion for learning, that has led me to investigate pedagogical methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This series will summarise my findings as I explore the world of pedagogy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;part-1---results-driven-learning&#34;&gt;Part 1 - Results Driven Learning&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This method is far from new or revolutionary, but does seem to be either underappreciated or underutilised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;current-state-of-affairs&#34;&gt;Current State of Affairs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the last few decades, education takes what could be described as a &lt;em&gt;theory-driven&lt;/em&gt; approach to teaching; each aspect of the concept is abstracted and analysed. It sounds good on paper, but is counter-intuitive and conflicting with the way we have evolved to learn: to solve a specific, tangible problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All too commonly, students ask: &amp;ldquo;why are we learning this?&amp;rdquo;, and often conclude: &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll never need to use this&amp;rdquo;. No wonder! Concepts are taught in a manner than neglects to incorporate application or relevance, and students are ultimately deprived of &lt;em&gt;motivating context&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An analogy for this is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A car&amp;rsquo;s brake pads are worn, and need replacing. To teach a student how to perform such a task, the student must first learn the theory, mechanics, and method-of-use for each spanner, clamp, screwdriver etc., before being given the opportunity to replace the brake pad. The student quite rightly becomes bored, potentially confused, and unmotivated. The task, which at first may have been exciting, has now become dull, and the student&amp;rsquo;s attitude has become negative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly, most methods of education found in schools now entirely revolve around standardised testing. Syllabuses are built around exam specifications rather beneficial knowledge, and students are tragically given one reason to learn: to pass an exam. Their newly acquired knowledge (usually build around memorisation rather than understanding) is quick to dissipate once the exams are over; there no longer remains any reason for retention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;results-driven&#34;&gt;Results Driven&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outside of education, being results driven is often of paramount importance; from leading a project to running a successful business, every task is given motivating context and relevance by a results driven approach - those that are not should be re-evaluated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Education can be thought of as the expansion and strengthening of a web of knowledge, with each new concept or piece of information being a link in this web; by ensure a good number of links between existing knowledge and new knowledge, we produce a more robust and resilient web. This result in better comprehension and retention of information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming back to our car analogy, we can taken a results driven approach as such:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A car&amp;rsquo;s brake pads are worn, and need replacing. To teach a student how to perform such a task, they will first approach the problem and identify the first step to solving it (e.g. unscrewing the wheel nuts). As they progress through the problem they will utilise relevant tools to help them, understanding the function and method of use for each. The student can see tangible results from using the tools, and is motivated by solving the problem; the student is left with a positive experience that further propels them into the learning process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps not every experience will be so smooth and satisfying, but this demonstrates the point of results driven learning; by providing context and application, the learning process is transformed. Outside of formal education, this is the standard approach. We don&amp;rsquo;t learn how to bake a cake by first understanding the chemical reactions that take place during the cooking process. We learn by baking the cake! Sure, those chemical reactions can be interesting and important, but without the context of the cake, they are (for most of us) abstract and boring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This ends part one of the series. I hope to produce a few more of these posts in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to finish this post with one final note on education:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teaching is for learning; learning is for understanding; understanding is for reasoning, applying, and problem solving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

